

Via Antoniana 68. La Spezia, Italy

🛘 (+39) 329 404 2683 | 🗷 lucabonamini28@gmail.com | 🔏 lucabonamini.github.io | 🛅 luca-bonamini

Summary_

Luca Bonamini is currently a Software Engineer with a focus on Autonomous Driving at Yape s.r.l.. He received his Bachelor Degree in Mechanical Engineering from University of Genova and the Master Degree in Robotics and Automation Engineering from University of Pisa, in 2015 and 2018, respectively. After graduation he started a collaboration as Research Fellow at Robotics Research Center "E.Piaggio" of the University of Pisa, where he joined Roboteam Italia, one of the teams of Roborace, an autonomous full scale electric racing car competition. He joined Proxima Robotics s.r.l. in 2020, where he was responsible for developing planning and control algorithms for mobile robots.

Work Experience_

Yape s.r.l. Milan, Italy

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | AUTONOMOUS DRIVING

• Design of navigation architecture for a delivery robot

Proxima Robotics s.r.l.

Pisa, Italy ROBOTICS SOFTWARE ENGINEER Mar. 2020 - Mar. 2021

• Develop a trajectory planning algorithm in a Frenet Frame for obstacle avoidance for a service robot

- Develop an Adaptive Pure Pursuit controller for path tracking for a service robot
- Develop tools for offline data debug and visualization
- Design and implementation of a CI/CD pipeline

Roboteam Italia Pisa, Italy

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | STATE ESTIMATION, PLANNING AND CONTROL Dec. 2018 - Mar. 2020

- · Develop an optimal trajectory planning algorithm for lane change and obstacle avoidance for autonomous racing cars
- · Develop a lidar-based localisation system for autonomous racing cars in a GNSS denied environment
- Develop interfaces between ROS ecosystem and real-time sensors for a self-driving car
- Contribute to the development of an MPC controller for real-time path tracking

Research Center "E. Piaggio"

Pisa, Italy

Apr. 2021 - Present

Dec. 2018 - Mar. 2020 RESEARCH FELLOW

- Develop an Augmented Reality system to assist mobile robots teleoperation
- · Collaborate on Alter-EGO project dealing with the development of an autonomous navigation stack

Education

University of Pisa Pisa, Italy

M.S. IN ROBOTICS AND AUTOMATION ENGINEERING

Sept. 2015 - Exp. Nov. 2018

• Towards a shared autonomy control framework: application to Ego robot navigation

University of Genova Genova, Italy

B.S. IN MECHANICAL ENGINEERING

Sept. 2012 - Sept. 2015

• Design of a two-stage parallel shaft gear reducer

Skills

Programming C++, ROS, ROS2, Python, Matlab/Simulink, HTML/CSS, JS

Libraries STL, Boost, Eigen, Qt

Planning Algorithms Dijkstra, A*, RRT*, Lattice, DWA, Potential Field, Optimal Trajectory generation

Control Algorithms PID, LQR, MPC, Apative Pure Pursuit **Real-Time Sensors** GPS, IMU, LIDAR, Speed sensors

Message Protocols Protobuf, CAN

DevOps Docker, GitLab CI/CD, Bash scripting

Tools GitLab, Git, CMake, gdb

Languages Italian, English

LUCA BONAMINI · RÉSUMÉ MAY 12, 2021

D	L	lications
PП	nı	lications

• LiDAR-Based GNSS Denied Localization for Autonomous Racing Cars. Massa, F.; Bonamini, L.; Settimi, A.; Pallottino, L.; Caporale, D. . Sensors 2020, 20, 3992.

Certifications

2011 First Certificate in English (FCE), Grade A, University of Cambridge ESOL Examinations

La Spezia, Italy